<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Commodity News &#8211; Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/category/commodities/commodity-news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com</link>
	<description>Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide, Online Daily Newspaper on Hellenic and International Shipping</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 21:45:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>FOB Australia premium mid-vol coal flips to premium for first time since November 2019</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/fob-australia-premium-mid-vol-coal-flips-to-premium-for-first-time-since-november-2019/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews...]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 22:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Πρώτη σελιδα]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841720</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Relativities of Australia premium medium volatile matter hard coking coal flipped to a premium to Platts FOB PLV for a historic first since the launch of the FOB Australian brand assessment on Nov. 1, 2019, as significant downward pressure was observed for PLV cargoes with current Chinese import restrictions on Australian coals. S&#38;P Global Platts ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/fob-australia-premium-mid-vol-coal-flips-to-premium-for-first-time-since-november-2019/" target="_blank">FOB Australia premium mid-vol coal flips to premium for first time since November 2019</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Colombia coal mine Cerrejon requests arbitration to end strike</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/colombia-coal-mine-cerrejon-requests-arbitration-to-end-strike/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews...]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841741</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Colombian coal mine Cerrejon on Friday requested the Labor Ministry convene an arbitration tribunal to solve a dispute with its largest workers’ union and lift a more than 70-day strike. The strike began on Aug. 31 after Cerrejon and union Sintracarbon were unable to reach agreements over pay rises, as well as health, education and ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/colombia-coal-mine-cerrejon-requests-arbitration-to-end-strike/" target="_blank">Colombia coal mine Cerrejon requests arbitration to end strike</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>CBOT agricultural products mixed in past week</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/cbot-agricultural-products-mixed-in-past-week/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews...]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841740</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>CBOT agricultural futures staged a mixed performance in the past week, while technically the agricultural futures are in a bullish position with the value of the U.S. dollar likely to decline. Meanwhile, Chinese economic demand looks to stay strong, and Chicago-based research company AgResource predicted that broad commodity prices will stay bullish. CBOT corn ended ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/cbot-agricultural-products-mixed-in-past-week/" target="_blank">CBOT agricultural products mixed in past week</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Argentina&#8217;s wheat harvest seen at 16.7 mln tonnes, lowest in five years, exchange says</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/argentinas-wheat-harvest-seen-at-16-7-mln-tonnes-lowest-in-five-years-exchange-says/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews...]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 18:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Πρώτη σελιδα]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841669</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Argentina’s wheat harvest is seen at 16.7 million tonnes, slightly down from the previous 17 million tonne estimate due to a prolonged drought, the Rosario Grains Exchange (BCR) said. The estimate suggests wheat production in Argentina, a major global exporter, will be the lowest in five years, the exchange said late on Wednesday. A drought ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/argentinas-wheat-harvest-seen-at-16-7-mln-tonnes-lowest-in-five-years-exchange-says/" target="_blank">Argentina's wheat harvest seen at 16.7 mln tonnes, lowest in five years, exchange says</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Africa: Mining output down 2.8% y/y in September</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/south-africa-mining-output-down-2-8-y-y-in-september/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews..]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 22:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841603</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>South Africa&#8217;s mining production decreased by 2.8% year-on-year in September, with the iron-ore sector having made the largest negative contribution and diamonds the largest positive contribution. Seasonally adjusted mining production decreased by 0.3% month-on-month in September. Seasonally adjusted mining production increased by 40.6% in the third quarter, compared with the second quarter. The platinum group ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/south-africa-mining-output-down-2-8-y-y-in-september/" target="_blank">South Africa: Mining output down 2.8% y/y in September</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. miners tout environmental credentials in wake of Biden victory</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/u-s-miners-tout-environmental-credentials-in-wake-of-biden-victory/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews..]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 22:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>U.S. mining companies are moving fast to align themselves with Joe Biden’s climate change agenda, saying the lithium, copper and other metals they produce can help the president-elect achieve his ambitious goals to slash carbon emissions and electrify the nation’s automobiles. With Biden proposing to hasten the demise of coal and other fossil fuels with ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/u-s-miners-tout-environmental-credentials-in-wake-of-biden-victory/" target="_blank">U.S. miners tout environmental credentials in wake of Biden victory</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dalian iron ore falls; posts biggest weekly jump in 3 months on demand hopes</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/dalian-iron-ore-falls-posts-biggest-weekly-jump-in-3-months-on-demand-hopes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews..]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 22:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Πρώτη σελιδα]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841570</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Iron ore futures ended lower on Friday, but the benchmark Dalian contract posted its biggest weekly gain in three months on hopes of robust demand for the steelmaking raw material as China’s steel inventories shrank. Iron ore on China’s Dalian Commodity Exchange closed 0.8% down at 832.50 yuan ($125.67) a tonne. It gained 5.3% for ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/dalian-iron-ore-falls-posts-biggest-weekly-jump-in-3-months-on-demand-hopes/" target="_blank">Dalian iron ore falls; posts biggest weekly jump in 3 months on demand hopes</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gunvor Successfully Closes Usd 1.225 Billion Revolving Credit Facility</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/gunvor-successfully-closes-usd-1-225-billion-revolving-credit-facility/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews..]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 22:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841602</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Gunvor Group Ltd. has signed a USD 1.225 billion revolving credit facility (“RCF” or “Facility”) in favour of Gunvor International B.V. and Gunvor SA. Initially launched at USD 1 billion, the Facility received strong support from Gunvor’s banking partners and showed substantial over-subscription of 22.5%. “The strong, continued support Gunvor has seen from our banking ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/gunvor-successfully-closes-usd-1-225-billion-revolving-credit-facility/" target="_blank">Gunvor Successfully Closes Usd 1.225 Billion Revolving Credit Facility</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Strategie Grains cuts EU maize import, wheat export forecasts</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/strategie-grains-cuts-eu-maize-import-wheat-export-forecasts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews..]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 18:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dry Bulk Market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Πρώτη σελιδα]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Strategie Grains has reduced its forecasts for EU and British soft wheat exports and maize imports as it factored in tensions on world grain markets marked by rising prices and strong Chinese demand. In a monthly report, it forecast 2020/2121 soft wheat exports from the European Union plus Britain at 24.3 million tonnes, down from ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/strategie-grains-cuts-eu-maize-import-wheat-export-forecasts/" target="_blank">Strategie Grains cuts EU maize import, wheat export forecasts</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Malaysia palm oil hovers at 8-year highs as inventory falls to 3-year low</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/malaysia-palm-oil-hovers-at-8-year-highs-as-inventory-falls-to-3-year-low/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews..]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 22:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Malaysia&#8217;s palm oil prices continued to hover at eight-year highs after industry data showed a decline in both stock and production in October. Crude palm oil (CPO) prices closed higher on 5 November at $831.73/tonne from $813.93/tonne in the previous session; while palm kernel oil (PKO) prices increased to $1,044.37/tonne from $960.71/tonne over the same ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/malaysia-palm-oil-hovers-at-8-year-highs-as-inventory-falls-to-3-year-low/" target="_blank">Malaysia palm oil hovers at 8-year highs as inventory falls to 3-year low</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Australia&#8217;s Fortescue plans global green energy drive</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/australias-fortescue-plans-global-green-energy-drive/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews..]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 22:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841450</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Australian mining magnate Andrew Forrest outlined ambitious plans on Wednesday to build a renewable energy business, aiming to compete with oil giants to provide low-cost green energy globally. Billionaire Forrest, who turned Fortescue Metals Group FMG.AX over two decades into the world&#8217;s fourth-biggest iron ore miner, said Fortescue Future Industries (FFI) has already signed preliminary ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/australias-fortescue-plans-global-green-energy-drive/" target="_blank">Australia's Fortescue plans global green energy drive</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>US Western bituminous coal production totals 11.9 million st in Q3, up 8.1% on quarter: MSHA</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/us-western-bituminous-coal-production-totals-11-9-million-st-in-q3-up-8-1-on-quarter-msha/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews..]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 22:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>US Western bituminous coal production totaled 11.9 million in the third quarter, up 8.1% from the previous quarter, Mine Safety and Health Administration data showed Nov. 11 From the year-ago quarter, output declined 24.6%, the data showed. Wolverine Fuels&#8217; Sufco mine in Utah was the top producer in the region with 1.4 million st. Output ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/us-western-bituminous-coal-production-totals-11-9-million-st-in-q3-up-8-1-on-quarter-msha/" target="_blank">US Western bituminous coal production totals 11.9 million st in Q3, up 8.1% on quarter: MSHA</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iron ore futures close higher</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/iron-ore-futures-close-higher-53/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews..]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 18:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Πρώτη σελιδα]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841364</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Iron ore futures closed higher on Thursday in daytime trading at the Dalian Commodity Exchange (DCE). The most active iron ore contract for January 2021 delivery gained 1.5 yuan (about 23 U.S. cents) to close at 835.5 yuan per tonne. On Thursday, the total trading volume of ten listed iron ore futures contracts on the ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/iron-ore-futures-close-higher-53/" target="_blank">Iron ore futures close higher</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brazil forecasts record grain output in 2020-2021 harvest season</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/brazil-forecasts-record-grain-output-in-2020-2021-harvest-season/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Πρώτη σελιδα]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Brazil expects record grain production of 268.9 million tons this 2020-2021 harvest season, 4.6 percent more than the previous 2019-2020 season, the state-run National Supply Company (Conab) said. An estimated 67.1 million hectares of land have been cultivated, or 1.8 percent more than last season and the most land cultivated on record. Soybean production, the ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/brazil-forecasts-record-grain-output-in-2020-2021-harvest-season/" target="_blank">Brazil forecasts record grain output in 2020-2021 harvest season</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 ways the mining sector can prepare for the coming economic era</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/7-ways-the-mining-sector-can-prepare-for-the-coming-economic-era/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 14:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Πρώτη σελιδα]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841342</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The mining and metals industry is facing an unprecedented paradigm shift as it begins to implement new technologies while also managing climate and social challenges. Through raising awareness of these issues, and by focusing on new digital solutions, growing material demand, and investor pressures, the industry can strengthen its foundational role in a rapidly evolving ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/7-ways-the-mining-sector-can-prepare-for-the-coming-economic-era/" target="_blank">7 ways the mining sector can prepare for the coming economic era</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Soybeans ease from 4-year high, tightening supply curbs losses</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/soybeans-ease-from-4-year-high-tightening-supply-curbs-losses/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 14:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Πρώτη σελιδα]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Chicago soybean futures eased on Thursday after hitting a more than four-year high in the last session, although strong demand and concerns over global supplies kept a floor under the market. Wheat slid for a second straight session to hit its lowest since Nov. 2, while corn lost more ground. “I think concerns over supplies ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/soybeans-ease-from-4-year-high-tightening-supply-curbs-losses/" target="_blank">Soybeans ease from 4-year high, tightening supply curbs losses</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iron ore prices hurtle to a seven-year high, coking coal prices lag on quotas</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/iron-ore-prices-hurtle-to-a-seven-year-high-coking-coal-prices-lag-on-quotas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews..]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841264</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>For the key steelmaking ingredients of iron ore and coking coal, it was a tale of two different markets this week. The price of iron ore punctured the $US120 per tonne ($164.70/tonne) barrier this week, its highest since early 2014 This was on account of a stronger market for steel in China which is targeting ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/iron-ore-prices-hurtle-to-a-seven-year-high-coking-coal-prices-lag-on-quotas/" target="_blank">Iron ore prices hurtle to a seven-year high, coking coal prices lag on quotas</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NSE to launch first agricultural commodity futures contract next month</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/nse-to-launch-first-agricultural-commodity-futures-contract-next-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews..]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Leading stock exchange NSE on Monday said it will launch its first agricultural commodity futures contract for crude degummed soybean oil on December 1. The contract will facilitate the soybean oils processing and allied industries in India and overseas, a perfect hedging tool for managing their price, the National Stock Exchange (NSE) said in a ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/nse-to-launch-first-agricultural-commodity-futures-contract-next-month/" target="_blank">NSE to launch first agricultural commodity futures contract next month</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>As Coal Giant Peabody Warns Of Return To Bankruptcy — How Biden Infrastructure Programs Could Save Miners</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/as-coal-giant-peabody-warns-of-return-to-bankruptcy-how-biden-infrastructure-programs-could-save-miners/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews..]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The world’s largest coal producer, Peabody Energy BTU -23%, is at risk of going bankrupt for the second time in five years. It’s all a function of the demand for coal, especially now during the coronavirus. But the potential trouble is indicative of something much bigger — the transition from coal to natural gas and ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/as-coal-giant-peabody-warns-of-return-to-bankruptcy-how-biden-infrastructure-programs-could-save-miners/" target="_blank">As Coal Giant Peabody Warns Of Return To Bankruptcy — How Biden Infrastructure Programs Could Save Miners</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deep-Sea Mineral Platform Launched Ahead of Battery Boom</title>
		<link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/deep-sea-mineral-platform-launched-ahead-of-battery-boom/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[hellenicshippingnews..]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commodity News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/?p=841262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A new way to meet the growing demand for minerals critical to electric vehicle, electronics and battery manufacturers could become commercially available within this decade. Significant public and private investment have gone into how to extract cobalt, nickel, lithium and other minerals from the deep seabed; however, more than 80 non-governmental organizations have voiced concerns ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/deep-sea-mineral-platform-launched-ahead-of-battery-boom/" target="_blank">Deep-Sea Mineral Platform Launched Ahead of Battery Boom</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/" target="_blank">Hellenic Shipping News Worldwide</a>.</p>]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
